I-Da Chiang

E-mail: idchiang@asiaa.sinica.edu.tw | LinkedIn: idchiang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Dust Life Cycle & Interstellar Medium

I am interested in studying the evolution of interstellar dust with multiwavelength observations. One of my projects is measuring the spatially resolved dust-to-metals ratio in the nearby galaxies, and interpreting the results with dust chemical evolution models, simulations and auxiliary data.

HI 21 cm Line & Radio Astronomy

The distribution of neutral gas is a key element in dust sciences and cold gas dynamics. The $\rm Hi~21~cm$ line traces neutral hydrogen atoms in the ISM. I reduced new $\rm Hi~21cm$ line data of $\sim \! \! 30$ galaxies observed by VLA with CASA. These new data allows us to construct a new dust-to-metals ratio survey in the nearby galaxies.

EDUCATION

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2021

Ph.D. (Physics and Astronomy)

Thesis: "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies"

Adviser: Prof. Karin M. Sandstrom

National Taiwan University

2012 - 2014

M.S. (Physics)

Thesis: "Plasmonic Enhanced Optical Disk Reactor for Wastewater Treatment"

Adviser: Prof. Din Ping Tsai

National Taiwan University

2007 - 2011

B.S. (Physics)

EMPLOYMENT

Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Academia Sinica

2021 - Current

Postdoc Fellow

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2021

Graduate Research Assistant

- Built a python-based toolkit for dust SED fitting and multi-wavelength data analysis.
- Analyzed the dust-to-gas and dust-to-metal ratios in the spiral galaxy M101.
- Analyzed the dust-to-metal ratio and CO-to- H_2 conversion factor in detail in \sim 50 nearby galaxies.
- Examined the empirical radiation distribution law and the turbulent power spectrum in the local group galaxies with the dust SED fitting tools.
- Reduced HI 21cm line data of \sim 30 galaxies observed by VLA with the Common Astronomy Software Applications package (CASA).

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2016

Teaching Assistant (TA) and Lab TA Coordinator

Familiarized new teaching assistants with lab setups and teaching skills.

- Led discussion sessions, which helped ~ 40 students each week.
- Led introductory level physics lab, with 24 students per session.
- Improved course materials from feedback from teaching assistants and students.

National Taiwan University

2012 - 2014

Graduate Research Assistant

- Improved the photo-degradation reactor for wastewater treatment with plasmonic nano-particles.
- Built the protocol for maintaining/using the sputter machine and clean room.

Taiwan (R.O.C.) Armed Forces

2011 - 2012

Second Lieutenant (Company second-in-command)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lab TA Coordinator, PHYS 1-ABC Lab – UCSD

Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – UCSD

2015 - 2016

2014 - 2015

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS (AS FIRST OR SECOND AUTHOR)

- 4) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, E. Koch, K. Kreckel, A.K. Leroy, A. Schruba, D. Utomo, T. Williams, "Resolving the Dust-to-Metals Ratio and CO-to-H₂ Conversion Factor in the Nearby Universe", 2021, ApJ, 907, 29.
- 3) E.W. Koch, **I-D. Chiang**, D. Utomo, J. Chastenet, A.K. Leroy, E.W. Rosolowsky, K.M. Sandstrom, "Spatial power spectra of dust across the Local Group: No constraint on disc scale height", 2020, MN-RAS, 492, 2663.
- 2) D. Utomo, **I-D. Chiang**, A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, "The Resolved Distributions of Dust Mass and Temperature in Local Group Galaxies", 2019, ApJ, 874, 141.
- 1) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, L.C. Johnson, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, "The Spatially Resolved Dust-to-metals Ratio in M101", 2018, ApJ, 865, 117.

A full list of refereed publications at ADS Public Library is available here.

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Contributed talk, "Dust, gas, and metals: Observing Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", Galaxy Evolution Workshop 2021, NAOJ, Tokyo, Japan 2021 Colloquium, "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Tai-2021 wan Contributed talk, "Dust, gas and metals: Resolving the Dust Life Cycle in the Nearby Universe", The AAS 235th Meeting, Honolulu, USA 2020 Special seminar, "Dust-to-Metals Relation in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan 2019 Poster, ASROC2019, Taichung, Taiwan 2019 Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Galaxies", Dusting the Universe, Tucson, USA 2019 Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA 2019

Poster, CPHDUST, Copenhagen, Denmark

Tea time talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA

2018

2018

Poster, ASROC2018, Kinmen, Taiwan Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA OUTREACH EXPERIENCE	2018 2018		
		Student seminar @ ASIAA – lecturer	2021
		Research in physics workshop for community college students @ UCSD – lecturer	2021
Python workshop for physics undergrads @ UCSD – presenter	2019		
Life as a scientist @ Jianguo High School – lecturer	2019		
STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights @ San Diego, USA – presenter	2018		
Tech Trek @ UCSD – presenter	2017		
Physics GRE bootcamp @ UCSD – teaching assistant	2016		
AWARDS			
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2014		
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2011		
Presidential Award, National Taiwan University	2011		